someone was to start a medicinal
mushroom garden in his little
permaculture farm somewhere in the UK
which species would you well.one this
get our term straight here at number one
our assumption if someone doing
permaculture boots on started medicinal
mushroom garden or a mushroom garden
they're actually doing it already yeah
so the permaculture permaculture ist's
are growing mycelium are growing all
sorts of microflora and you know in
their environments they're already
seeing the advantageous species like at
finned when we saw the big parasol
mushroom mac macro lepida Procera coming
up beautifully with the plants well
that's a great pairing right there so
the mushrooms that can be grown in
companion cultivation in the garden are
many fold there's there's the hips as I
guess species the elm oysters from the
conference we were just at it was quite
surprised and delighted to see the
pleurotus pulmonary us maybe an end to
fight and the fights are fungi that grow
in association with the plants and they
give a host defense resistance against
insects and other diseases and including
other fungi the pleurotus pulmonary us
is one of them but the Amadou mushroom
my hat is made from Amadou the birch
polypore foamies vomit areas just as
past four years ago research came out
that it is an end to fight protecting
potentially birch trees and this
mushroom only forms on dead birch trees
but the fungus infuses the stems and the
leaves of the birch tree preventing
other quick to kill parasites from
killing the birch tree but when the
birch tree matures and dies for whatever
reason then the fungus goes okay I've
protected you my time to reproduce and
then it produces this Woodcock a hard
hoof and then this wood conch has
antiviral properties we do know that
it's active against the actually the
I think it's called the variegated to
tobacco virus as one of the first
antivirals were found were found from
the Amadou mushroom and now we know it's
active against other viruses and other
bacteria as at the vols protozoa so our
ancestors I think and especially women
it's just a fact of life is that men
have testosterone we go out and beat
each other up and kill each other with
sores a lot more than women do I think
most people accept that we come back to
the camp were wounded and women are
there because the children and nursing
and all of that and I think they were
the great mycologist of ancient time
they were the labor making the mushroom
potions they were boiling Amadou to
create and preserve meat reduces
bacteria the fabric that can be made in
the clothing and I could give that to
you to prevent you know parasitic
diseases from infecting your wounds and
I think there was a lot of this concept
that witches brew I think there was a
especially in middle Europe there was
the enormous knowledge base around
paganism
and witches and and some of these acts
were Christian witches so it's not about
Christianity here's about Earth based
knowledge and knowledge of natural
systems and that these medicinal
mushrooms and even the psychoactive
mushrooms are feared by many because
they're so powerful and yet
misunderstood
back in time I think we had a much
greater knowledge and I propose the
hypothesis that the the greatest
mycologists the greatest medicinal
mushroom practitioners were probably
guilds of women and and then they would
give the men what they needed but they
were the collector of knowledge it seems
natural to me they would be because we
were foraging and bringing things back
to the camp but the men men would go out
get harmed the women would be protecting
the family so seems to me they'll be
protecting the medicinal mushroom
knowledge is fun turkey tail mushrooms
which I've mentioned already turkey tail
mushrooms hyperacute accumulate selenium
selenium will bind with mercury ions
mercury and selenium come together as a
biomolecular unit that's totally
non-toxic so this was discovered by dr.
arica in Japan and he found something
even very surprising you can take turkey
tail mycelium
kiloton autoclave is dead my psyllium
powder up the mycelium throw it into
mercuric ions and water and it'll
precipitate and bind with the mercury
this lien will bind together so they
needn't come from the mycelium the
mercury you know from a mine or from
pollution and then we'll make it into a
totally non-toxic form so there is no
one example of the binding of heavy
metals using these different mushroom
mycelium directly after Chernobyl
there was a mushroom but which we call
in America the hideous gum phidias David
Aurora gets credit for that name and and
this is a mark arousal species that
grows in roots of trees but when the
Ukrainian scientists went out into the
downed wood environments after Chernobyl
they were looking to see what foods were
still edible because the Ukrainians had
a long history of collecting wild
mushrooms wild foods and they found this
one mushroom hypercam loosely a
caesium-137 a heavy metal radioactive
metal from Chernobyl 10,000 times more
than the background contamination so it
was able to hyper channel and
decontaminate a large landscape from air
fall you know of cesium was able to up
channel it and focus it into a mushroom
now the mushroom is radioactive highly
radioactive mushroom is dangerous to
consume but in doing so the mycelial mat
decontaminated a large area guarantee
the plurality and biodiversity as pcs
within the ecosystem that then give rise
to the trees in the foley secrete the
debris fields that kept the ecosystem
intact that allowed the confidence to
grow so there is yet another example
there's there's dozens of examples
against ecoli against nitrates against
all sorts of other pollutants coming
from industry and farms and from
livestock's they're all it's a list that
I could go on for hours with one example
after another after another after
another but this is just the beginning
it's the proverbial tip of the my silly
old iceberg we know we're just the few
candidates we've seen and recognized
today it's just suggest
of how vastest library is out there